Like functions in other languages,
就像其他语言中的函数一样，
functions in Rust are used to group code
Rust 中的函数被用来对代码进行封装，
so that it can be called multiple times
以便可以使用不同的值
with potentially different values.
反复调用。
In this module, we'll look at how to
在本节中，我们将学习
write functions
如何在 Rust 中使用函数。
in Rust. The functions
我们将会用到
we write will use variables, which
u1m3 讲到的变量和
we introduced in module 3,
u1m4 讲到的原始数据类型
and primitive data types from module
来写函数。
We are going to cover the syntax for defining
我们将介绍函数的定义，
and calling functions,
函数的调用，
and talk about the idiomatic way
以及
to return values from functions.
更惯用的方式来返回函数值。
Let's get started
让我们先从
with how to define a function.
如何定义一个函数开始。
Here's what function definitions look
这是一般的函数定义的样子，
with the fn keyword,
以 fn 关键字开头，
followed by  whatever name you want to give
后面是函数名，任何你想起的名字。
Within parentheses, list each
括号里，列出每一个
parameter the function takes by
参数，
giving the parameter name, then a colon,
每个参数给出参数名，一个冒号，
then specifying the type
和其类型。
Separate each name/type pair
用逗号分隔每个参数名/类型对。
with a comma. Your function
函数可以
can take as many parameters as you want.
接受任意多的参数。
If the function returns a value,
如果函数返回一个值，
put a hyphen, then a greater than sign
先放一个连字符，再放一个大于号
to make an arrow,
来做一个箭头标志，
and then specify the type of the return value.
然后指定返回值的类型。
If the function doesn't return a value,
如果函数没有返回值，
leave off the arrow
去掉箭头和
and the return type.
返回值类型。
Then, open a set of curly brackets,
然后，写一对大括号，
put the code you want to be the body of the function,
里面写函数主体代码，
and close the curly brackets.
并关闭大括号。
There are more complicated function signatures
还有可能有更复杂函数签名，可以在以后的课程中看到例子。
Here's a concrete example.
这里有个具体的例子。
This function, named next_birthday,
这个函数名为 next_birthday，
has two parameters: name,
他有两个参数：
which is a string slice,
name，string slice类型，
and current_age, which is a u8.
和 current_age，u8 类型。
This function doesn't return a value.
这个函数没有返回值。
The function body figures out how
函数体主要内容是计算
old the person will be on their next birthday
一个人下一次生日是多少岁，
and prints a sentence using the person's name
并用这个人姓名和下一次生日时年龄
and their next age.
打印一句话。
Now, let's see what calling a function looks like.
接下来，让我们看看如何调用函数。
Once we have a function defined,
一旦我们定义好了函数，
we can call a function by using its name
我们就可以使用函数名
followed by parentheses
加括号，括号内
with the values for the parameters, called
填充形参的形式调用
the arguments to this function call.
该函数。
Here's what calling the next_birthday
这里是如何调用 next_birthday 函数的
function looks like –
样子，
first, with the values Jake
首先使用“Jake”和
and 33,
33 调用，
and next with the values Vivian
再使用“Vivian”和 0
and 0.
调用。
Running this prints out
运行这个函数会打印出
Hi Jake, on your next birthday, you'll
“Hi Jake, on your next birthday, you'll
be 34!,
be 34!”
and Hi Vivian, on your next birthday
和“Hi Vivian, on your next birthday
you'll be 1!.
you'll be 1!”
Finally, let's look at a function that returns
最后，让我们来看看一个返回值的函数。
We'll write a function that takes the number
我们将写一个函数，
and returns the square of that number.
接收一个数字并返回其平方。
Note that the last line in the body
请注意，函数体的最后一行，
doesn't have a semicolon at the end.
末尾没有分号。
This tells Rust we want the resulting
这个语法是计算表达式的值
value of that expression returned out of
并作为函数返回值。
This main function will print The
这个主函数会打印“The
answer is 9.
answer is 9”。
If we've defined the function signature
如果我们像这样定义函数签名，
such that it returns the value,
以便它能返回值，
but we accidentally put a semicolon
但却不小心在最后一个表达式
after the last expression,
放了一个分号。
we'll get an error.
这将得到一个错误。
Rust gives us a helpful hint
Rust 给了有用的提示，
that we probably meant to not put that semicolon
也就是这里可能不应该放这个分号。
There is a return keyword that you
Rust 用 return 关键字
can use to return from a function early,
来提前从函数返回，
and you can use it at the end of a function if you want.
如果你愿意也可以在函数末尾使用它（译者注，指return）。
However, idiomatic style
然而，Rust 的函数返回值惯用法
is to implicitly return the last expression.
是隐式地返回最后一个表达式的值来使用。
Now you know how to define
现在你知道如何
and call functions that have parameters
定义和调用 Rust 里带参数和返回值的
and return values in Rust.
函数了。
Next,
接下来，
let's look at control flow  features available in Rust.
让我们来看看 Rust 中的控制流。